

### PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth - July 25, 1989 Father's Name - Mr. Mukand Singh Mann Marital Status - Single Permanent Residence - Ludhiana, Punjab

### CONTACT



simranjyotm@gmail.com



+91-9711923760



143, Yamaha Vihar, Sec -49, Noida

### **EDUCATION**

### **MBA - HUMANRESOURCES**

Amity University, Noida; 2012 CGPA - 6.79

#### B.Sc. BIOTECHNOLOGY, GNDU

Khalsa College, Amritsar; 2010 Percentage - 75.11%

XII (C.B.S.E.) - 82.4 %

**X (C.B.S.E.)** - 90 % (Maths - 96%)

### **CERTIFICATION**

Certified **NLP** (Neuro Linguistic Programming) **Practitioner** from ANLP, India

## AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Numerous Spot Bonus awards for planning and executing successful employee engagement programs
- Received appreciation in the form of Appreciation and Thank you cards
- Implemented new Bio-metric system for attendance for better employee usage and easy analysis
- Created the role metrics to design the Job descriptions for all the levels across organization
- Prepared Employee handbook and Welcome Kit
- Started the Employee Engagement intiatives in current firm including events and Birthday celebrations
- Implemented 888 Induction Feedback forms
- Won numerous awards in Declamation contests, poetical recitations, poster making, cultural competitions etc.

### **HOBBIES**

Adventure and Nature lover- Attended 7 days' military training camp at Manesar, Gurgaon, Did Bungy jumping in Apr 2016

# SIMRANJYOT KAUR MANN

Assistant Manager- HR, NLP Practitioner

### **ABOUT**

Almost 5 years of progressive experience in performing Human Resources functions in IT industry. My core profile includes working as an HR generalist with add on skills of Neuro Linguistic Programming. I am currently seeking a position as an HR generalist to use my experience for better growth and profitability of the organization. I believe in 'Practice makes a man perfect.'

### CORE COMPETENCIES

Employee Relations
Induction & On-Boarding
Rewards & Recognition
Employee Engagement
Talent Acquisition

\*\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*\*\*

Performance Appraisal Management Performance Analysis Employee Separation Management HR Analytics SAP Transactions (HCM Module)





### **PERSONALITY**

Leadership Skills

Learner Responsible Business Achiever Hard worker

### **EXPERIENCE**

### ASSISTANT MANAGER -HR; AXTRUM SOLUTIONS | JAN 2016 - PRESENT

- Employee Relations & Org. Cycle- Handling employee life cycle in the organization right from Induction & On-boarding till Separation; Communication interventions, Grievance handling and Exit analysis
- Employee Engagement- Handling end to end Employee Satisfaction Surveys, events, campaigns etc.
- **Performance Appraisal Management** Launched 360 Degree Appraisals from scratch for the very first time in the organization to record formal feedback of employees
- Rewards & Recognition Revamping the Service Awards in the firm from certificates, salvers to deciding the gifts to be given
- Talent Acquisition- Helping in the recruitment of mid-level engineers, support staff as per the organizational needs
- Attendance Management- Using attendance data to prepare various reports along with Probable Attrition
   Analysis

### SENIOR EXECUTIVE - HR; HCL TECHNOLOGIES | FEB 2016 - DEC 2016

- SAP Transactions- Handling the updation of database in SAP via various transactions like PO13, PA30, PQ13, PA40 etc. for HCL AXON US; Collating and analyzing reports/database via SAP
- Geo Joining Management System Preparing and analyzing various monthly reports as required by stakeholders in US
- Exit Management System; Collating and analyzing Attrition reports
- Leave Management System, Employee Verification

### EXECUTIVE - HR; INTERRA INFOTECH | MAY 2012 - JAN 2015

- Employee Relations- Driving & Ensuring communication interventions, HR campaigns, events & grievances along with collating and analyzing feedback on organizational climate through various employee interactions
- Induction and On-boarding-Responsible for managing On-boarding & Induction for all level of joiners; collating and analyzing feedback via self-initiated 888 feedback forms and one-to-one discussions
- **Performance Appraisal Management** Worked on aligning individual objectives to organization by executing effective goal setting activity.
- Rewards & Recognition- Driving the process of annual performance awards, On-the- Spot, Service Awards, Appreciation, Thank you, Sorry cards
- Employee Engagement & CSR- Conducting various HR events for same; Initiating and analyzing Employee satisfaction surveys
- Employee Separation Management- Suggesting the effective measures for retaining the employees via Early Warning Indicators, Exit Probability Analysis
- HR Analytics- Retention & Exit Analysis, Employee Satisfaction Surveys and Employee Reach Out Report